# VICTOR GNANARAJ

DevOps Engineer (AWS)

Mobile: +91 8825888588

Email: gvgraj143@gmail.com

Address: Chennai, TamilNadu

# **SUMMARY**

AWS DevOps expert with 3+ years of professional experience in advancing team velocity by introducing common branching strategies, automating build/integration checks, and simplifying deployment patterns. Key achievement collaborated with 50+ developers to automate a deployment process using Ansible, Chef, and PowerShell.

# **EDUCATION**

## Sri Vidya College of Engg & Tech

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering 2016 - 2020 - 75%

## SKILLS

- Cloud Platforms: AWS
- **Containerization:** Docker, Kubernetes(EKS), ECR. ECS
- IAC: Terraform, Terragrunt, Cloud Formation
- **DevOps Tools:** AWS CodePipeline, Jenkins, GitHub Actions, Helm, Ansible
- SCM: Git, AWS CodeCommit, GitHub
- Serverlees: AWS Lambda, API Gateway
- Monitoring and Logging: CloudWatch,
  Prometheus, Grafana, X-Ray, AWS RUM
- Scripting: Shell Scripting, Python, Bash
- Configuration: AWS SSM, Ansible
- Networking: VPC, Gateway, Security Group
- Reliability: Load balancing, Autoscaling, DNS management, Disaster Recovery, Backup
- **Security:** AWS IAM, Security Best Practices, WAF
- AWS Billing and Cost Management
- AWS Services: EC2, RDS, IAM, S3, Route53, SSM, EventBridge, Kinesis, Lambda, DynamoDB, SNS, SQS, Batch, ElasticBeanstalk, Elastic cache, CloudFront, EFS, EBS

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

• AWS Cloud Practitioner - 2VBFK2C1SFQ11DHKH

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **DevOps Engineer**

# Vinsinfo Pvt Ltd | 11/2021 - Present

- Integrated AWS CloudFormation and Terraform, increasing build speed by 60% and reducing deployment times from hours to minutes.
- Designed and implemented a highly scalable, secure CI/CD pipeline resulting in 2x faster delivery of updates and features.
- Led an initiative to migrate on-prem resources to AWS Cloud which reduced IT expenses by 35% while improving server uptime to 99.9%.
- Reduced deployment errors by 40% by integrating AWS CodePipeline and CodeDeploy in the development process.
- Implemented Docker for containerization of applications, resulting in a 50% reduction in server usage and a 30% cost reduction.
- Automated build and deployment process with Jenkins and Maven, eliminating 85% of manual work
- Created and deployed Docker containers to break up 19+ monolithic apps into microservices, enhancing developer workflow, scalability, and optimizing speed by 94%.
- Introduced common branching strategies, automated build/integration checks, and simplified deployment patterns, which boosted team velocity by 28%.
- Maintained RDS, Route 53, VPC, RDB, DynamoDB, SES, SNS services, and over 100+ user accounts in the AWS cloud.

### **AWS Developer**

#### Vinsinfo Pvt Ltd | 11/2020 - 11/2021

- Reduced server downtime by 30% by maintaining highly available systems on AWS Cloud Infrastructure.
- Spearheaded the use of AWS RDS for database management which improved efficiency by 60%
- Collaborated with the software development team to deploy software updates more frequently due to streamlined AWS processes.
- Hosted the application on Ubuntu and Windows servers
- Managed the site configurations in Apache, nginx, and IIS. configured the proxy and redirections
- managed the Ec2, RDS, and Dynamo DB Backups, and maintained those
- Analyzed the LB and WAF logs using AWS Athena and Glue
- Monitor those AWS Infrastructure and created the Cloudwatch alerts and Action Items
- Handled IAM users, groups, policy and S3 Policies

# Achievement:

- Achieved 50% cost savings by migrating a Python Flask application to a serverless architecture on AWS Lambda, running seamlessly within a containerized environment It reduced 40% of the cost.
- Spearheaded the automation of patch processes utilizing AWS Systems Manager (SSM) and other AWS services
- Successfully led the migration from a classic host model to a microservices architecture in both ECS and Kubernetes, optimizing scalability and performance.
- Innovated an internal tool integrating multiple AWS services, providing effective version control and rollback capabilities for internal workloads.